## AMAR MOHAMMED

Swindon · 07763585365

<u>Am.inspiredsolutions@gmail.com</u> · <u>LinkedIn Profile</u> · <u>https://uk.linkedin.com/in/amar-mohammed-4a185b55</u> Website · <u>https://inspiredsolutions.me</u>

From obtaining my BSC Business Information Systems degree I have been in the IT industry for over 11 years, covering the basics from hardware all the way through to data warehousing. I have been part of many projects both small and large which involved a vast array of technologies.

I have experience working with SME's from email deployment, CRM development through to website/web application builds. I have also worked for corporate organisations using oracle ERP solutions to achieve change management and data consolidation.

In my most recent role as a consultant I acquired software language skills enabling me to completely customise managed CRM/ERP solutions such as Oracle FDMEE and Oracle DRM, achieving the clients specific requirements. In the past I mainly focused on plain JavaScript but quickly started to see the benefits of other technologies/languages in both front-end development and languages such as JavaScript and Jython.

Currently I am focusing on building on my front-end development profile whilst also working at achieving full stack status. My current arson of skills include HTML, CSS, JavaScript, AJAX, Node JS, Express, Git, Git Hub and many more. Working on these skills everyday to build and develop websites/application on the world wide web. I also have experience with APIs, both pushing and pulling information in a secure and stable manner. Currently I am working on further developing my skills in TypeScript and Angular.

## **EXPERIENCE**

#### JUNE 2019 - PRESENT

### **TECHNICAL SUPPORT ENGINEER, TOPONIFY**

In this role I worked in a sister company of my previous employer Seismi to create a web application tool. This required me to build on my JavaScript knowledge through online academia and on the job training. This included software's and software languages such as JavaScript and the DOM, Ajax, NodeJS, Express, Git and Git hub. In this role I also strengthened my HTML and CSS skills while starting to learn the Angular framework.

I also gained experience with the Amazon AWS platform as test instances were ran on this platform before deployment. I was also responsible to support and integration so lots of work on API's.

## JUNE 2016 – JUNE 2019 CONSULTANT, SEISMI

A consultant implementing complex Oracle ERP solutions for many large corporate clients. My role entailed implementing Oracle applications such as Oracle Data Relationship Management and Oracle Financial Data Quality Management. Oracle DRM was used to produce one standardized view for master data while ensuring validations

were applied through rules and properties. Oracle DRM was also used as the central hub for sending and receiving cleansed master data between many planning and reporting systems. Oracle DRM allowed me to use governance/workflows to direct change within a business to the relevant business people while ensuring validations were met, audit trails were automatically created and a standardised process was consistently followed. Using JavaScript code, I created and maintained sophisticated properties and validations, enriching the data for downstream and upstream systems. Overall I customised the standard Oracle product and tailoring the DRM package to exceed the client expectations.

Oracle FDMEE was used as an ETL tool that would very neatly integrate into other Oracle tools such as HFM and Hyperion Planning. This ETL tool enabled me to extract data using data load rules with particular filters to ensure only the required data was extracted. Complex mappings (Explict, Like and Multi-Dimensional) were applied enabling the organisation to transform this data before any validations were ran within FDMEE. Finally loading this data into an Oracle Hyperion Planning application ready for the Planning & Reporting team. Through the setup and development of FDMEE event scripts were created using the coding language Jython. These Jython scripts enabled me to push the mapped data into the Oracle Enterprise Data Warehouse (EDW).

# JANUARY 2014 – JUNE 2016 THIRDLINE, PROJECT MANAGER

While working at enviz I was appointed a project manager at the partner company Thirdline. This promotion was due mainly to my development in task management and customer relationship building.

This role involved me gathering and documenting business and functional requirements to a high standard for bespoke software construction projects. I also worked closely with business focal points, Project Managers, and Application Team Leads to ensure successful project delivery. My role meant I worked with solution architects and technical leads to ensure that the designs take full account of specific requirements and constraints.

## JUNE 2012 – JANUARY 2014

## **SENIOR SOLUTIONS SPECALIST, ENVIZ IT**

enviz IT are certified IT Support Specialists based in Swindon, providing bespoke IT support for SMEs. Part of the larger enviz group working with Communications and IT Support to Network Penetration and Cloud Based Solutions. Working in a team of 20, the role of Senior Solutions Specialist includes: Server, Network and Wireless installations; cloud infrastructure migrations, maintenance and troubleshooting; virtual migrations for VMWare, Citrix Xen Desktop, Xen Desktop and Hyper-V systems; Telecommunications; construction of Cloud-based infrastructure including Data Centers and hardware; Cyber-security.

## **EDUCATION**

**JUNE 2012** 

**BSC BUSINESS INFORMATION SYSTEMS DEGREE,** UNIVERSITY OF GLOUCESTERSHIRE

Final Grade 2:1 - This degree combined the best parts of business and computing degrees. By the time I graduated, I understood what makes the business world tick and how information systems are integral to business growth in the 21st century.

## **SKILLS**

- HTML
- CSS
- JavaScript
- jQuery
- SQL
- Ajax
- Nodejs
- Git and Git Hub
- Angular
- DNS
- Microsoft Office 365 and Azure
- Amazon AWS

- Software testing and debugging
- Problem Solving and Critical Thinking
- Collaboration Team Player
- Ability to adapt quickly
- Windows machine and software specialist
- Windows and Apple OS experienced
- Virtual machine setup and maintenance
- ISO 9001 and ISO 27001
- Ability to lead when necessary and follow when necessary

## **ACTIVITIES**

I am a young driven individual that has a real passion for anything IT. While on my journey I have become a loving father and trying husband and a car fanatic, all while trying to find the time to fit the weekly 5 a side football game in.